Marcela Martínez Galván

E-mail: marcelamartinezgalvan@gmail.com **Mobile:** + 521 618 803 19 31 Dgo,Dgo,Mexico.

Over 12 years of experience on IT Services, Performing different roles and activities related to Busines Analyst, Product Owner, Scrum Master, Technical Support Manager, Technical Lead, Data scientist and External Consulting Roles.

- Willing to learn and adapt to new processes and or technologies.
- Able to perform technical and administrative activities such as researches, working in data centers or coordinating implementations for Different kinds of projects and areas such as Banking, Healthcare, and Telecommunications.
- Currently enrolled in an Al Master (Tools:Jupyter Notebook, Google Collab, Python libraries, Activities:Model creations, dataset analysis, developing Material training in Youtube Channel https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCZPDNUuHmkcdOOl3p4pYfkQ

Professional Experience

Persistent System Company

Area: Taxes

Date:November 2021-June-2022

Role: BA- Product Owner

Activities:

- Defining business requirements and track them in Jira and confluence application.
- Creating and managing the Jira Product backlog
- Prioritizing Product backlog
- Reviewing and approving prototypes
- Attending at scrum ceremonies (Grooming, sprint planning, sprint review, daily meetings on zoom meetings)
- Training new team members
- Cleaning data for ETL process by analyzing and updating structure and unstructure files that will be used for System ingestion.
- Supervising requirements implementation with development team
- Gathering analysing Jira metrics for decision making load of work distribution.

Wipro

Area: Marketing

Date: May-2020 November 2020

Role: Web Autor

Activities:

- Gathering Marketing requirements.
- Designing Marketing Content web with AEM Tool
- Validating Quality Content for Intel Pages
- Extracting and analysing data related to load of work distribution ODBC connection and sqlite.

Itexico

Role:BA External consultant Date: May 2019 -May 2020

Customers: Gig Ronin, Etaluma, Nutra bolt, Iridium, Sadler, R4R.

Activities

- Gathering and Eliciting Requirements during remote discovery sessions.
- Elaborating Functional and Technical Documentation for stakeholders presentations.
 (Architecture Application Document, User Guide and Technical Trainings)
- Defining Minimum acceptance criteria for user stories contained in Jira Application.
- Creating and Owning Product Backlog in Jira application and RTC.
- Acting as communication channel among the whole project.
- Collaborating during UAT testing.

e-Quality

Area: Marketing and Sales

Date: September 2018-March 2019

Customer: B2B, BP.IBM. Role: Business Analyst

Activities:

- Gathering and Defining Business requirements
- Refining user stories and process analysis.
- Working closely with Product owner and scrum Master during SDLC process by using Scrum framework on the next scrum ceremonie: Stand up, Grooming Backlog, Planning, Sprint Retrospective and Sprint review.
- Coordinating and supervising software Deployments
- Clarifying Maintenance Processes
- Testing APIs with postman
- Reviewing and updating GDPR Documentation.

Global Fleet Management

Area: Telecommunications

Date:January 2018- September 2018 Role: Technical Support Manager

Activities

- Analyzing and updating different linked processes such sales, billing, Maintenance, Development, and GPS installations to identify new Product or service requirements. Gathering Functional and not functional requirements.
- Defining scope statements to recognize the gap between problem and goals states.
- Acting as a communication channel among all the stakeholders (installers, providers, sellers, product owner, technical support, testing, and development team).
- Supervising Field and Developers activities .
- Creating google site to store Technical processes, Connection diagrams and
- Guidelines documentation

https://sites.google.com/view/wikitrace/p%C3%A1gina-principal

Collecting information for analysis troubleshootings related to issues or incidents found in the production environment and documenting issues details and logs for the developer team.

Carestream

Area: Healthcare

Date:June 2015-December 2016

Role: Business Analyst

Activities:

- Acting as a Vertical Administrator on LAR monitor portal web (used to provide a proactive and preventive monitor service)
- Creating Customer Documentation
- Coordinating, improving, and participating on the Support Process
- Coordinating LAR Tunneling Network implementations
- Coordinating LAR Monitor Migration Processes
- Elaborating LAR Monitor Training Documentation
- Installing PACS Servers
- Performing UAT Testing

Dedamex, Dedagroup Company

Area: Banking

Date: February 2013-November 2014 Role: Business Analyst, Developer.

Activities:

- Analyzing and updating Technical Dictionaries to create new documentation for technical support and dev team on Integration processes.
- Comparing generated files for Data warehouse by applying queries on AS400 System and providing results and sharing the same on Excel documents to Italian ETL team members.
- Deploying Jeniux forms
- Dispatching Emergencies Code Drops
- Participating on CAB meetings by presenting fixes to implement
- ❖ Become a communication channel between development team, testers, and onsite team in order to make sure that new fixes have been implemented properly from start to end.
- Coordinating outages
- Creating Business Documentation.

Tata Consultancy and Services

Date: January 2011-November 2012

Role: Business Analyst

Activities:

- Business Intelligence Project to handle investment transactions for Morgan Stanley Bank.
- Acting as Planning Lead on environment management activities. Outline cross-application solutions for customer needs, which will later be used by development teams as the guideline for the actual system solution.
- Serve as a professional business and technical authority for both the customer and internally. Liaison with all the project managers, testers,
- developers, and infrastructure teams that are involved in setup
- activities.
- Analyzing support processes
- Analysis on XML transaction Code
- Controlling Server status
- Creating Internal Documentation.

Technology

Python, Jira Application, Microsoft SQL Studio Management Server 18, Zoom, Google Drive, Microsoft teams, Confluence, Putty Application, AWS Amazon fundamentals (EC2, S3, Route53, IAM, RDS, DB), API postman, RTC Backlog to track requirements, Outlook, Webex application, IDE Eclipse, Selenium, TestNG, MySQL. Postman, Selenium. Maven framework, Google Site, Google Drive, Excel, Visio, Redmine, WebEx, Internal GPS Platform. MySQL 5.5.2, Scrum Methodology, SQLite, PACS 10.1 Server, RIS V11 Server, RMS Monitor Portal, Sametime, SharePoint 2008, Acrobat PDF, IDM Migration Platform. AS400 IBM, Eclipse, I system Navigator, Redmine, MQ Monitor, XML, Leela Application, Agile methodology, ITIL, Solaris, Java, HP Quality Center. Infoview application, MQ Monitor, System I Navigator, Solaris OS, VBM, UNIX. Jupyter Notebook, Numpy, Pandas and Matplot Python Libraries, Google Collaboration and PyCharm, Scrum Framework.

Education

■ (ITD) Instituto Tecnológico de Durango.

Title: Intern in Electronic engineering.

■ Scrum Master

International Scrum Institute

Certificate Number: 91722704044543

Data Science programming and Machine Learning.

Certificate Number: DCD-2022-02-009